And this is the oversight on our part is
we have not gone back and made our terms
clear in the world of large language
models. Large language models are wildly
different from classic AI. What AI was
when we wrote those terms was different.
[music]
>> Best part of acting when you can just
you know critical think.
Yeah, dude.
>> Sup, Packers? We've got an exciting
announcement. Threat Locker Zero Trust
World Conference is back in 2026. It's
going to be March 4th to March 6th in
Orlando, Florida. It's freaking gorgeous
down there too during that time. And
yours truly is going to be there. I'm
going to be there on Wednesday, March
4th. I'm going to be leading a hands-on
hacking workshop. I'll be one of many.
So, there's lots of fun hacking
workshops you can get involved in. Um,
and it's going to be a great time.
There's tons of sessions, workshops,
other people there to network with. It's
going to be a great conference. So, if
you're local to Orlando or if you're up
for the travel, um, this is a great way
for you to use that employer uh,
training budget that you've got. Also,
um, for critical thinking listeners,
there's a discount of $200 off. You can
use the code ZTW, right, for zero trust
world CTB26.
ZTWCTBB26
when you register. That'll be on the
screen and in the description as well.
It's going to be a great time. I hope to
see you guys there. All right, let's go
back to the show.
All righty, hackers. It's been a big
week in Bug Bounty. Lots of drama on
Twitter about the whole hacker one
thing. We've got a whole episode
dedicated to that, which I think should
help address some of the issues. Uh, but
before we do that, we're going to jump
into the This Week in Bug Bounty segment
to give you guys some quick news. Um,
Yes, We Hack is continuing to crank out
awesome guides to bugs that go very
in-depth. Um, and this week they put out
an XML um, external entity XXE guide.
Uh, and it has got a lot of data in
here. Um, XXES is one of those bugs
where it comes out of nowhere and it
gets you like very impactful SRF, file
read, sometimes even rce. So, if you're
trying to land more criticals, this is
really one that you should look deeply
into. Um, and I read through the guide
here. Uh, yes, React does a really
excellent job of providing a
comprehensive summary of how to find
these and different techniques for
exploiting them. So, check it out. Um,
really good stuff in here. Even they
even cover like, you know, language
specific stuff like, uh, PHP expect and,
um, I believe some Java stuff as well.
So, really good stuff here. Um, next is
something that is actually going to be
launched a couple days uh before this
episode releases, but this is the bug
bounty maturity framework. And I know a
lot of apps uh people and actually
program managers listen to this podcast
as well. So this is um primarily for you
all but also has impact on the
researchers. So let me explain what this
is. um a a guy that was on the team for
critical thinking a while back, Steve
Hernandez, uh he also worked for Hacker
One for a while, realized that there's
no way for programs currently to get an
idea of where they are as compared to
other programs and um understand their
maturity as as a program. Um so he took
all of his knowledge of the industry
from his time working at Hacker 1 and
with uh critical thinking and built this
website, bugbountmaturity.com.
Uh this is where you can take a quick
survey to understand where your bug
bounty program lands as on a scale of
emerging to leading um and how to level
up to different tiers and provide the
best service to the hackers and get the
largest ROI out of your program. Um so
this is like a 15 question assessment
but then it gives you very very clear um
you know uh stairs up to the next level
like do this do this do this and then
you'll you know really be providing an
uh the best ROI right that's the thing
that's going to move you to the next
level that the researchers are going to
feel the most or that your organization
is going to feel the most um I worked
with Steve to to build this out and
design the questions and I think that if
more programs took this and followed the
steps inside of it the quality would
really go up. Um, and we're actually
even tossing around the idea of doing
some certification that goes along with
this, right? So, when you see the bug
bounty maturity framework, um, you know,
certification or whatever, say, "Hey,
we're at established or advanced or or
leading," then you know what that means
and you know that you can trust that
program. So, um, for any of you hackers
that are interested, definitely feel
free to take a peek. But you program
managers, appsacc teams, I'd love for
you guys to head over to
bugbountymaturity.com
and take the assessment, see where your
organization is at. Um, and see how you
can improve your experience for the
hackers and for your org. Um, all right,
I think that's it. Let's cut to the
episode. We've got some really good
stuff with Alex Rice, CTO of Hacker 1,
where we address some of these issues
that, um, have been put before the
community and put before Hacker 1.
All right, man. So, uh, we just got off
that interview with with Alex. Um, we're
about to play that clip for you guys in
just a sec. Um, overall, I feel like
that was pretty solid and I feel a lot
better about how Hacker 1 is using our
report data.
>> Yeah, he was super straightforward,
super willing to answer any question.
You were you went a little harder than I
expected, uh, especially in the second
half. So, uh, people tuned in for Justin
kind of playing hard ball there. But,
no, I think I think that I was happy
with all the answers.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, when I was roasting
him about the bounties, right? About
like uh reducing the bounties. Yeah. I
think he needed a roast for that. I
think he deserved a a roast for that.
>> But and and on the other part, like I
just think that whenever you pressed
into some of those questions, right?
Like anytime his language was even a
little bit vague, you pressed in to like
make sure it was clear. I thought that
was really good.
>> Thanks, man. All right. Well, we're
going to jump into that clip. Um, I just
want to say before we we do that, um,
and I add this comment as well in the
actual recording, but, uh, this was a
interview that we reached out to Hacker
1 for, and we did not provide them with
any questions in advance or any ability
to edit the content. Everything said was
on the record. Um, and I tried my best
to represent you guys as the hunter, uh,
and how I felt as a hunter myself,
obviously. Um, so definitely welcome any
feedback you guys want in the discord.
But, um, I just wanted to disclaim that
because Hacker 1 is a sponsor as is bug
crowd as is yes we hack as is integrity
but we made very clear to them in the
beginning that their sponsorship in
would have no effect on the content and
um I I think we held to that very well
here.
>> Yeah, in general you know Justin isn't
big to toot his own horn but when Justin
started critical thinking that's the
mission. Like if Justin wanted to make
more money, he would just go do more
bucket bounty hunting. Like he does the
podcast for you guys and for his friends
and the whole point is the journalistic
integrity and the building of the
community, not to make more money. So
they're just sponsors because it makes
sense and it kind of like Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Leaves me more time to hack really
is is why because like my goal with this
podcast was like let's get the team in
place. Let's get people like Richard,
you know, doing awesome things, taking
care of it so that I can spend more time
hacking and then telling people about,
you know, how amazing Book Bounty is.
So, all right, we've said our piece.
Let's cut to the clip.
>> All right, guys. Well, here we are. We
are going to be covering uh some some
drama that has been going down on
Infosac Twitter as always. Um, and we
are welcomed today by Alex Rice. Thank
you for joining us, Hacker 1 CTO. And
hopefully we can uh I don't know, man.
Are you ready? ready for some some
>> I love a good roast. Thanks for having
me out here, guys. This is gonna be fun.
>> All right, man. Great. Great.
>> He voluntarily did this. We didn't like
uh kidnap him and bring him on.
>> No, no, that was great. And yeah,
>> that's a good point. I will I will
mention, you know, because I said on the
episode last week that we were going to
reach out for Hacker One for a comment
and um you know before before everybody
jumps on the like you know train because
there are a lot of uh you know high high
energy high uh you know tensions are
high in the bug bounty community right
now. Um, I want to disclose that Hacker
1, you know, is a sponsor of this
podcast, as is Bug Crowd and Integrity
and Yes, We Hack. And, you know, we made
it very clear from the very beginning
that the content of of critical thinking
is sacred. So, when we reached out to
Hacker 1, you know, to get a comment on
this, we invited them on the podcast to
discuss this, but um, you know, we we
are not providing editorial uh, you
know, access to this, and we're also not
pre-prepping or anything like that. So,
um, this is off the off the cuff on on
the record. uh as much as we can. And uh
Alex, I I appreciate you signing up for
that.
>> Yeah, I appreciate the integrity here.
You got to keep it authentic.
>> Yeah. Yeah, we do. Um so with that, man,
all right, now we gota now we got to,
you know, really represent the the
hackers here. We're a little scared,
man. We're a little scared because um
you know, we're reading these terms of
services. We're looking at this
marketing material that you guys are
putting out. And um I think just
speaking for the community in general
right now you know with so much thing so
many things happening with AI it's and
nobody knows which direction it's fully
going to go and we have years and years
and years of report data of our hard one
techniques you know in the code uh you
know in the HTTP requests um in the
platform and to see something like those
those terms of service lines um you know
implying that hacker one may have the
right to train AI models off of that
data is really scary for us. So, can you
provide some clarification about why
that is in your terms of service and how
you guys are using report data right
now?
>> Yeah, we'll start with that piece and
then we should come back to the overall
what what is everyone just feeling right
now? What what's going on with but our
approach here? We are definitively not
training gena fine-tuning any anything
of that nature on researcher submissions
which are also customer submissions at
the same time. We talked about a bunch
of the reasons why that is. Let's get in
into the detail of that.
>> What really kicked all this off was
>> raising really good questions on our
terms of service does say
>> we have the ability to actually first of
all our terms of service have been
pretty restrictive from the beginning.
Hackers retain all of the IP to their
services. we have a license to utilize
it to improve our uh provide and improve
our services and then customers get a
license to it. So there's no uh
ownership transmission here, but there
are some licenses that need to exist to
to operate the service and and part of
that um which we should get into why
that exists there is the right to train
train models.
>> And why why is that there? One is
because there's a number of things that
happened here, but it has been in place
from the beginning and this is the
oversight on our part is we have not
gone back and made our terms clear in
the world of large language models.
Large language models are wildly
different from classic AI. What AI was
when we wrote those terms was different.
I'll give you a real real example here.
The very first ML model we put into
place was over a decade ago. It powered
our spam
uh prediction engine. Every time a
customer is clicking report spam on a on
a report that goes into a regress
analysis and every new report coming
forward has an updated spam classifier
score on it, right? Like that is that's
that's training AI. We call it machine
learning.
>> Legal and marketing teams call it AI. Um
that needs to get disambiguated now. So
it really on us that we didn't catch
that earlier and we didn't fix that
sooner. Uh we've tried to be really
transparent with our technical
documentation but not the terms and we
got we got to get those two in in line.
Okay. Yeah, that makes sense. And and I
I understand that certainly spam
classification is one of the big issues
that you guys have dealt with from the
beginning and also that has been
amplified you know since the AI you know
onset here.
>> Um and the one piece I'm going to read
the the you know most concerning line
from the terms of service right here. It
says hacker one may use confidential
information to develop or improve its
services for example to identify trends
and to train AI models provided such use
does not result in disclosure of
confidential information to unauthorized
third parties. So, as I understand it,
you know, that confidential information
is the the user's, you know, full like
unredacted report. And and what I'm also
wondering is whether you know hacker one
is using any of that report data and
making it anonymized you know whether
you're anonymizing the target
anonymizing the researcher but keeping
you know the meat of those techniques in
any way and utilizing those in training
even your own internal products like
like the um the pentest as a service
platform or anything beyond just the
spam filter.
Yeah, it's it's a good question to get
into what the broader piece of it is.
Um, there is an anonymization process
and an aggregate trend analysis that
goes on. Uh, we're not using that today
to train AI models. And I think it's
helpful to talk about why why why not
like what what are we doing? What are we
training models on which is what bulk of
what our our material um focuses
[clears throat] on. And I I think we we
might I'd love to get into this a little
bit more later, but I think what we're
all seeing right now is the baseline
foundation of the models are getting
really good at finding vulnerabilities.
We don't view it as our place to that
for that to be the thing that we
differentiate at or really excel on. I
think the AI scaling laws are holding.
The models are getting better and better
at this every single time one comes out.
it's just not central to our product
strategy or what's needed to even
deliver these capabilities to really
innovate and and push there. There's a
ton of areas before and after the
discovery of a bug where AI is providing
a ton of leverage to teams and hunters
on on both sides, which is where we're
applying quite quite a bit more of that
that um analysis for things like what's
the right triage decision, what's the
right prioritization decision as we were
doing this pen test, how much of the
scope was it covered, what areas weren't
weren't there. And so there's there's a
lot more that goes into this than just
discovery. And I want to talk about them
in in pretty pretty specific ways as we
can get into them.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, as you respond to that,
you know, a couple things pop into my
head. You know, anonymous, you said that
there is an anonymization component. So,
I'm I'm wondering what post
anonymization what that data is being
used for. And two, you said, you know,
that AI is being utilized to help
determine whether, you know, what piece
of scope and stuff like that is being
covered. and and so how is it doing that
without access to the researchers
reports?
>> The p you can do it in the hacker
powered security report. That's the
primary output of the anonymized data
set.
>> Okay.
>> Um and the
second part of your question is how's it
doing that without access to the toes?
>> So I guess the the first part I'm sorry
I got a lot of I got a lot of things I
want to ask about man here. I'll take it
one at a time. So first the you said
there is an anonymization component.
Where is that an anonymized data going?
You said mostly the hackerpowered
security port. Is it completely the
hackerpowered security report or is
there some other
>> it's the the hacker powered security
gives you an example of what that data
looks like. So it's all anonymized and
aggregated. So it's things like powering
the benchmark suite the trend analysis
like what how what CVS are being
discovered most frequently. And the
these are all pre prei features that um
so I wanted to give some examples of
those of of what what
>> it's not it's not going into an LLM to
determine the you know what's it called
like the to determine like the types of
bugs that are being submitted or
anything like that. It's all basically
ML models or or like tagging prelims
that are that already were being used to
generate the security report for the
year.
>> Yeah. But
sorry I want to be precise here is
because we as we talked about this
there's not LM's involved in in any of
that piece of today.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So that data that data isn't being
ingested by LLM or being utilized to
enhance LLM or fine-tune LLM even even
in its anonymized state.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> Okay. Excellent. Well, that makes me
feel a little better. Uh
um that that is good. Um I and and I
will say just as a as a hacker
I I appreciate the hackerpowered
security report like I appreciate
insight into what is happening in from
the bug bounty you know industry in
general and being able to see those
trends being able to utilize that to
enhance my own methodology you know by
looking at that material so I don't know
I don't want to speak for the whole
community here and I know that I am a
little bit less privacy conscience
conscious than most um you know people
are in our industry but I think that
that is not only helpful for the bug
bounty community and helpful for you
guys as a platform but um in you know
specifically helpful to the hacker to be
able to enhance their own methodology.
>> Yeah. So I think if we like rewind and
talk about a principle here for a second
the principle we're trying to not
violate is the researcher's mission is
the researcher's data. It is their
property. um it's in a strange situation
because it's shared with both a customer
and with us and so there's two points
where um there's potential for other
people to see your property and and and
learn techniques and things and things
from it. So I can provide really
definitive statements on um what we're
doing with RA that doesn't violate that
principle and that and that in that
practice. And I also want to say why we
try to be so transparent about this is
we haven't made a major mistake there
yet. there's a there's a chance that we
do and we want to find out about it as
soon as we do. So, we want to know
specific examples. Anytime somebody has
seen a um I think I was using this
technique and now someone has found out
about it over here. How h how did that
happen? We investigate those pretty
regularly. We've had some insider
incidents in the past that point to
that. Um whether it's an insider or an
AI model or a customer or any other way
that it happens. Um we we take those
really seriously. We want to know about
those. We want to investigate those and
we're we're we've taken a lot of
safeguards to not do that with AI. And
if we are doing that, like if you find
areas where you think that might have
happened, let us know about it. We we
want to go investigate it. We want to go
figure out how that happened. We want to
get to source of truth on it.
>> Um I don't see how it be our AI models
today, but it's like that accountability
loop driven by transparency is a key
part of making this thing.
>> What?
>> Yeah. Or go ahead. I was I was just
going to say I think that like um the
way you keep saying it's our property
like for some reason like it doesn't
ring true for me because I've always
understood bug bounty as like I'm giving
up my IP in order for to be paid like
basically I I like I basically when I
submit it I'm kind of like a agreeing to
the company's terms to like not disclose
this without their permission
>> and um so I don't know I would just love
a little more clarity around that
because if like if that's not the case
that actually makes me feel like awesome
you know like I feel like whenever
whenever I like I've always assumed that
in bug bounty it's actually not my
intellectual property anymore that it's
actually the companies and maybe hacker
ones and so like if I want to keep if I
want to keep the rights of myself I need
to email it into security at instead
>> yeah not not not the case but let's get
let's let's dive into this for a second
that I'd encourage you to go back and
refresh with I'm going to quote the
actual terms here because I we put a lot
of time and energy into I think they
actually work but the section 8 of the
community terms
>> uh you retain all intellectual poxy
rights you give hacker one a pretty
limited license solely for purposes of
improving and providing our our
services. So that it prohibits a ton of
stuff like us reselling it or um we go
through the the the restrictions on it.
The customer has a slightly more
permissive license for it. They're
allowed to um [clears throat] do
whatever is necessary to improve and
secure their own attacks, their own
attack service.
that you're right like it is your IP but
you are giving up a a pretty
unrestricted license to it to the
customer less so to hacker one our R
ours more restrictions on it um but when
it goes to the customer that is where
you're you're losing and that's where
when we really strong asurances about
making sure none of this ever makes it
out anywhere else that is where these
things do
eventually tend to come out is customers
thread intel sharing feeds or their own
remediation teams or CVE advisories like
eventually this makes it into the common
pool of knowledge
>> which other hackers start picking up on
and hunters are incentivized to try to
delay that as as long as we can but it
inevitably happens if purely through
active remediation efforts
>> and that's where most of this is making
it into the models we we we we suspect
and so there's a little bit of a time
delay and a halflife on these where we
view it as our responsibility not to
violate that trust not to accelerate it
unnecessarily but I think some of the
anxiety that we're feeling is that that
is accelerating like that loop between
new type of of exploit has been
identified and scanners AI scanners are
now finding it effectively is is a lot
shorter than it was in the days of Rapid
7.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I think that is definitely
a a component of it and I will say as
somebody who you know I had one of my
zero days that I reported get yked and
uh you know used and I went through
hacker 1's you know process to address
that and we we got to the root of it
very quickly and uh you know that person
was uh not a hacker one employee but
they they were reprimanded by their
employer that was a hacker 1 customer.
Um, I was satisfied with that with that
process and that is a risk, you know,
that that we have when we when we submit
and I've I've seen you guys personally,
you know, take serious, you know,
precautions to try to to try to um
address that. So, that that is certainly
reassuring. I'm wondering if there's any
way like what way should we report these
things to you that you say you would
like to know about? like I if there's
some way that our techniques have been
leaked out or we feel like our
techniques are being utilized by AI or
something like that, what what is the
best way that we can get that back to
you for investigation purposes?
>> Yeah, great great question. The easiest
way if there's a specific report you
suspect is is involved there, the the
mediation button is the the cleanest way
to track it. for some reason you don't
trust that, grab grab your HSP, submit
it into our bounty program or or or
reach out to one of us directly. If you
think there's something really sus going
on, hit our our legal team directly at
at legal ad or privacy.
>> Okay. All right. Yeah, I think it could
be a valuable thing for you guys to set
up some sort of um you know, specific
email or something like that that we
could that we could email directly to to
sort of address these issues. That that
could be something that would increase
hacker trust moving forward. just to
have a way that we can express these
concerns and get sort of one onone uh
you know answers to some of these more
sensitive questions.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I I'm as you
talk about it I I don't even know what
to point you to other than report it.
Yeah. So that's a brilliant call out.
We'll we'll action that right away.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> And hackers don't use that as like a
second mediation path. you use it for a
legitimate leak. So,
>> this is why we can't have nice things.
[laughter] Yeah.
>> Like,
>> but that that's kind of our our
responsibility is like whether it's a
whistleblower complaint or or or
something else, it's on us to
investigate all all of us.
>> Yeah. We'll use the ML models to
[laughter] to spam figure out whether
the the report is spam. No. Um, that's
great. Um, well, thank you for for that
and and I guess I'm going to press a
little further here into this because
there's not just the piece of like, you
know, are you fine-tuning AI models
here, but there's also the pentesting as
a as a service platform that you guys
have just released. So, um, some of the
concerning quotes from the um, marketing
material for that are as follows. Um,
agents are trained and refined using
proprietary exploit intelligence
informed by years of testing real
enterprise systems paired with robust
verified uh, community of elite
pentesters. So when we read this, it
kind of sounds like, oh, our proprietary
exploit intelligence that we've been
giving you, you know, all these years is
going into the training of these pentest
uh, as a service um, platforms. Uh so I
guess
>> the data for that the data that has
informed the prompt or the rag or you
know whatever you're using to to make
this um you know agentic uh pentest as a
service platform. Um where is that
coming from?
>> Yeah. Um this this is this let's let's
pick this pick this apart into a few
different topics here. one the marketing
material line that you just quoted out
here um Patrick called this out also we
we went back and corrected that right
away so some new text on there that
reflects a little bit more better but
separately from that uh about a two
weeks before we published the marketing
launched we published a security
architecture of the pest system that
goes into really specific detail and
you'll notice we don't have the
confusing training language in in there
so let me jump to that question around
how this work
>> actually before we do this let me like
just have us I'll context switch for a
second on what is packer 1's pest
because we're not
>> yes please
>> really known for it. It's a meaningful
portion of of the business today. We
launched it back in 2018. We got into
the pentesting business and the the
reason we did it was one of the biggest
things holding back more companies
adopting bug bounty is assessing if
they're ready for it or not. And we were
running into this problem. We regularly
would have companies coming and be like
we we want a bounty program. We we love
it. We're so secure and we have all
these things where like, well, let's
assess your maturity and make sure
you're ready for that. One of the most
common things we'd run into is we have a
pentest. We've been doing this pen test
for 5 years and we've never had a
finding. Like, we are good to go. Like,
let's go launch a bounty program. And
we're like,
can we see that? Can we see that pentest
out there?
Yeah. And so we really started doing
pentest through a defense in-depth
mindset of you've you've really got to
approach these things. You can't just
decide bug bounty is going to be the
first thing that I do to secure myself.
If you've been doing a check the box
$2,000 compliance pen test for the last
5 years, you're you're not going to be
ready for this. And we viewed it as a
comprehensive customer offering as part
of it. and our flavor of pentesting very
high-end. They're they're they're not
cheap. It's not meant to be the
compliance. We tell people out the gate
like, "Look, if you're just trying to
get compliance, there are many pentest
vendors that will do that." Um, it's all
community powered. Sometimes they
overlap with hunters, not always. Not
every hunter is is a pentester, but it's
about 200 pentesters from the community
that do these pentests today.
>> Okay.
>> So, that's the background. 2018 going in
and out.
>> I have heard of this. So this this is
where you guys are giving pentests out
to, you know, the the bug bounty
community and there's like a lead
pentester and stuff like that and
they're performing the pentest. The lead
pentester like puts it all into the
report and works with the client and
that sort of thing. Um
>> that's exactly right.
>> Okay. That component. This is really
interesting because and I'll let both of
you talk in just a second, but when I've
heard pas mentioned in the last week, I
think it's been in in like the same vein
as all this ad stuff and it because it
ends in AAS, I think it was all I I
thought it was some new offering that
was all automated. I I like I've done a
few pentest through hacker one.
>> So, does that does that mean that like
am I just like actually confused? And
when you all say pest, you actually just
mean manual hackers from the crowd?
>> I wouldn't use the term manual there,
but yes. All our pest offering always
has a human event. Even our agentic pest
offering takes.
>> Yeah. So, so maybe we're just
differentiating between the agentic pest
and the other one, but I think Justin
and I are mostly asking about the
agentic pest and not just like
>> Yeah. So, let's go there now. Let's talk
about pentesting in 2026. Um, none of
our pentesters are not using AI agents
today.
>> Right. Right.
>> Like it's just we should talk more
broadly. anyone trying to do bug fishing
day if you're not already ramping up on
that you you you kind of need to be and
our our our pentest community has been
leaning in on this pretty pretty pretty
early on. Um and there's components of
it that should stay with the individual
pentester. They're really tailored to
their toolkit and there and there's
components of a pentest that really need
to happen at scale ahead of the pentest
even starting for everybody engaged in
the pentest and need to be interactive
with with the with with the lead
pentester. Um, so that's what our agent
P test look like. It's it's meant to be
operated by humans. We we get into this
like is an agent fully autonomous? Is
any human? I'm not that far on the AI
hype scale. The all the AI we're
deploying has a heavy human loop
component and their agents meant to be
orchestrated by human experts. In this
case, the lead pentester or actually all
the pentesters but predominantly the
lead pentester in the pentest.
>> So that yeah, if I if I could ask about
that then like that makes sense. I think
everybody should be doing it. Just like
we said, we've said that on the pod a
ton. Um that com that you know lead
pentester that is utilizing this agent
that you guys have built. You know,
obviously they're they're working hand
in hand with the agent, right? The this
agent has it has it seen has it seen
techniques from reports? Has it where is
it getting all this data? This years I
mean what did it say like um years of
testing real enterprise systems
intelligence formed by years of testing
uh real enterprise systems like where
did that years of of experience come
from? is that that 8 2018 to you know
uh where you guys have been working with
you know in the pentest as a service
environment like are those reports going
to feed the AI or is it bug bounty
reports or is it some separate data set?
>> Yeah, so none of the bug bounty reports
um the data sets and I I should have
sent you the art data but the the five
areas where it gets that intelligence
from the first one is public benchmarks.
We try to pull all of those in to make
sure they pass those.
>> The second one is we invested in
building a bunch of internal benchmarks.
Um, a lot of the pentesters helped and
contributed to to building those.
>> Um, there are custom vulnerable apps
that we that we've created for that try
to replicate a pentest pest testing
environment. There's public CVES and
disclosures. This is the only area where
there's potentially overlap with the bug
bounty commission because a big
percentage of CVEEs today originate as
bug bounty submissions. So there is some
contamination that that occurs through
through that process. And the fifth one
which is where most of the real power
comes from is what we call sidecar runs.
And these are done where um both the um
pentester and the customer has opted in
to run the two of them in in parallel.
Um so we've been doing those more
recently and it really compares what
what does this look like in kind of an
isolated environment and what does it
look like in in this in in this trained
environment.
>> Okay. So sidecar runs are are are what
the the AI is watching what's happening
on both sides of the spectrum. Is that
like like on the researcher side and on
the customer side?
>> That's right. And
>> this is where I it's it's worth being
precision because if we were doing this
to
>> in in in the bug bounty space, it'd be
really
confusing.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. But the the pentesting is a
different engagement model. Works
differently. there's pretty clear
consent and and optin and the dynamic
there is is different right like
>> pentesters
are a bit more of a hourly grind for
lack of a lack of a better term and the
efficiency you get from AI is is huge
there like and so there there's a little
bit less of this contention there we
operate with the same principles but
that's u it's a pretty different world
than than bug bounty hunting and bug
bounties
>> I totally agree and I that especially if
both parties opt in that's fine. I I am
wondering what that looks like though
just out of curiosity like are are you
guys processing you like do you have the
pentesters like turn in their Kaido
project or their Burp project and like
you know then you guys analyze off those
HTTP requests or is it you know the
questions that the researcher is asking
the AI you know like how are you
utilizing the data in these sidecar runs
>> it's it's it's all of the above for
those and I don't want to get into
because the team's iterating this is one
of the This is not being clear in AI is
how fast it moves. Um, but let me just
say one of the reasons why I I say it's
that is something we think works really
well in our pentest offering is that we
try to bring as much diversity as we
can. Actually, this is what works well
in the bug bounty offering. So, if you
talk about like is there going to be one
AI agent that can do your pentest for
you, put me on the far end of skeptic
for that. Like I I don't think that's
the world we're getting to in the near
future. It's it's going like it's
getting better. Um, but could you just
like by Okay, I've picked I've done my
enterprise RFP. I evaluated a bunch of
AI pentesting stuff and I've picked the
best AI pen tester. Like, am I good to
go? Is Is that all I need? I I I don't
think so. I think you're going to need a
real diversity of agents running. I
think you're still going to need bug
bounty and community submissions running
after that. even even if bugs are
getting more scarce and like I would
love to see pentesting level up to the
level where it actually where it
actually does that. Um so when we are
doing these our pentesters have a lot of
individual by design freedom to use
different tools
>> and so that means when it gets what is
it actually I I forget the stats off the
top of my head but there is no single
pentesting suite that's used by a
majority of the the pentesting group
that that we have by by design.
>> Mhm. Yeah, that that makes sense. And
man, yeah, there's so many there's so
many pieces to this and components to
this, but it does I mean at the end of
the day, [clears throat]
excuse me, for me it boils down to that
that piece of like okay, bug bounty
reports are not being utilized.
Anonymized bug bounty reports are not
being utilized. What is being utilized
is, you know, consenting pentesters and
consenting clients for that data to be
processed and used to enhance the the
agentic component. And the pause for a
second here to inter your question just
to um
>> uh I'll tell our marketing team to cover
the areas for a second because they're
they're here.
>> Most of the capabilities here are coming
from foundation box. Yes. Like let's
just all be let's all be clear about
this.
>> A lot of the value providing is around
this like last mile. How do you make
that really usable to enterprises and
customer? I think that's where we're
uniquely positioned to provide a lot of
the value here. But when we look at
pentesting, the bar is so low. We don't
need an an AI like up toate trained on
the 10,000 best hackers in the world.
Like it's it's just not needed to have
meaningful step change functions in the
state of pentesting today. Totally. It's
just not.
>> Yeah. And I think that's I mean Joseph
that's kind of like what you and I have
talked about out of band as well which
is like we've done a lot of experience
experimenting with like fine-tuned
security oriented models and so far you
know the the frontier models right have
have taken the cake as far as
performance by a large margin. So you
know even you know and these are massive
data sets they're training off of too
you know um to make these security uh
models. So, I think that general
intelligence at this point is going to
outweigh uh, you know, fine-tuned models
on even if it was fine-tuned on
researcher reports, right? Which it's
not. I think it would still outperform
uh, you know, the the frontier models
would outperform that that fine-tuned
model.
>> Yeah. I I wanted to mention that just to
ass fears of bug hunters that are
listening that do think like
>> oh now if if some you know model
provider snatch like were to acquire
hacker one or bug crowd they'd be able
to use that data to then make it like
way better and I'm just not convinced
that's the case like I actually think
that so much of these models uh
improvements comes from having just like
large access to huge data sets and and
so much of the improvement that have
been made to its ability to hack is
actually just in its ability to code
Right? Because coding and hacking do
have like a lot of overlap. And so its
ability to write little one-off scripts
to test things I think has been what has
been massively leveling up things like
cloud code for example. And that um if
you if they if a company were to like if
Hacker 1 were to fine-tune uh GPT4 um on
like all of the reports in Hacker 1, I
actually don't think it would be that
that that um much of an improvement if
if any. So
>> yeah. And so anyways, if Yeah. So, you
all probably aren't even going down that
route. Or if you or if there are people
internally at Hacker One that are like
trying to push you to do that, Alex,
this is like some good logic for like,
should we really do that? Um, and and
one of the big issues with that is that
like what percent of all your
submissions are high quality, you know,
[laughter and gasps] it's like a very
low percentage, right? And everyone
knows that who's managed a program. And
so if there was something down the road
where you all did consider it, I think a
much better model would be like, you
know, pay the best bug hunters a certain
amount per high quality report. Now you
have a very refined good data set that
is actually, you know, worth training on
or something like that. But yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I agree. I think I think
some researchers would definitely the
more green hat researchers would
definitely, you know, be cool with that,
I think. [snorts]
>> So um
>> yeah, it hasn't proven to be necessary
yet. And if if if it were, I don't know
if it'd be our place to do it is
>> yeah it because at the end of the day
researcher trust is paramount really and
and that is an essential component of
the model for hacker one right it is is
this trusted middleman you know that's
going to work with you and and and and
advocate for you in scenarios where you
know uh you need that and and vice versa
for the for the programs right um so I
think maintaining that that trust is
paramount. I did want to I did want to
ask though,
you know, we've we've been around the
block in the security world a little bit
and you know, as AI is getting more more
and more traction, um it seems to be
that private equity does want to come in
and force the hands of some
organizations to to utilize that data
for other purposes. is and I'm wondering
if you guys as somebody who's on the
seauite of hacker one I'm wondering if
you guys have had pressure on that front
to address you know selling that data or
using that data for AI purposes.
>> No, we haven't. And I want to separate
the two of those out because well we we
need to go clarify our terms to draw a
distinction between the different types
of AI that are out there. The selling
the data is something that would is is
>> more clearly defined in in there. Um,
but also just from an overall company
health perspective, we've been kind of
fortunate. We were a little bit paranoid
founders. We were pretty selective with
our board early on. We've got VCs that
have a very long uh time horizon. Um,
and we've we've tried to run the
business really efficiently. There were
a number of years we ran it free cash
flow positive
>> and and have tried to balance as much of
that with the researcher growth of the
research community as possible. So,
we're not in a position that I feel like
that's kind of a state of right now like
this is something that should be on on
everybody's mind. It's like uh who can
predict five years into the future on
something? But I'll say very
definitively right now there's been no
pressure to sell to another firm or or
or operate it any differently.
>> Okay. All right. Well, I'm glad to hear
that. I I think that that is the the
right choice. Um so I hope I hope that
continues to be the case over the long
term. How is this overall anxiety
happening across everybody? Like not,
but I'm kind of reminded of it. There's
like a a pretty uh viral blog post that
went out a week and a half ago of like
something big is happening. And as as
I've been sitting with that for the last
week, something big is happening. And
it's it's like everywhere, everything
all at once. And it's it's uh it's it's
it's kind of nuts, but kind of exciting
at the same time. And I I do think we're
in a period of pretty intense
transformation. like the way this looked
is is changing pretty pretty
significantly. And the one message I
wanted to be be here is like if you're
still in a position where this is not
meant to assuade transparency or help
force us to be transparent, force
accountability on us. That is that is
our responsibility. We are very
committed to that. But at the same time,
you cannot be afraid of AI right now. If
you are not using AI in your bug
hunting, if you're not using in your
pentesting, you you've got to lean in.
like go download vanilla cloud code or
Shannon or Artemis or Stricks like these
tools are
>> really powerful in the hands of a
professional.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I agree. Thanks for thanks
for that. And I I you know on the flip
side of this I'll I'll commend you guys
and say really like please continue to
value researcher trust and as paramount
because you know if that degrades it
becomes really hard from from our side
to continue you know giving bugs and and
I appreciate you coming on here and
protecting that um with us and answering
the hard questions and letting us badger
you a little bit about it. I know I
asked you like three or four times, is
there any component of the, you know,
uh, is the template of the report being
fed to AI? Um, you know, but and I
appreciate you, you know, taking the
time to to, um, address those those
concerns. And if you guys continue to do
that, you will continue to have a
researcher base that is strong and
producing.
>> As excited as I am about AI agents
improving security, we are a long way
away from not leading security
researchers. I think it's going to be
now more than ever at least for the the
[clears throat] the immediate future.
>> Yeah. Joseph, any closing thoughts?
>> Yeah, I mean I I think that um in
general, you know, it's like like you
said, the anxiety at least in my
opinion, I think that I was like less
worried about it until like you said the
last few weeks I've definitely felt like
something is happening. And I think it's
the fact that, you know, everyone I know
is now using, you know, coding agents to
basically level up their hacking in such
a way where they're finding more
vulnerabilities. I think that's just
like on net perfect. Like I think that's
amazing for us society. I also think
that it goes to show the ease with which
companies will be able to implement this
on their side which I do think will
reduce the amount of exposed
um insecure you know code that kind of
touches us but also you know I think
that you know vibe coding is going to
continue to to crank out and you know
it's not even really vibe coding anymore
because I think like people are using it
internally seriously right so like
saying vibe coding is almost the wrong
word but I think that people you know
inside enterprises are rolling out way
more code than they were able to before
and obviously that's going to have stuff
that gets missed. But my my um my
impression is that I think you know
there is going to be kind of like a land
grab for those low for the lowhanging
fruit you know the bottom 20 like where
whereas before the low hanging fruit was
like bugs that found via full automation
which was maybe like let's say 1% or 2%
of bugs I think there's going to be a
little bit of a land grab for the bottom
50% now over the course of the next nine
months right or the next six months a
yeah and so I do think that does worry
me a little bit because at the end of
that it's like things are really secure
which is amazing for for like the
security of the human race, but also
like it also kind of makes it kind of
tough, right? It's things like I do
think they will kind of dry up. And my
hope and my you know recommendation to
programs would be like at that point if
you do start to receive far less bugs,
offer more money for better bugs, right?
And then hopefully you keep us in the
game a lot longer and then you keep
finding more.
>> Yeah. Actually, now that we're now that
you mentioned that, Joseph, I I while
I've got I've got you on here, Alex, I
did want to address one more thing. Like
we also saw a decrease in bounties on
Hacker 1's bug bounty platform. You guys
uh you know decreased them pretty
substantially. And um I you know I'm not
sure if I if you're the right I mean
obviously you're the right rep in the
organization to talk about what's
happening with these products and where
the data is going and stuff like that.
I'm not sure how actively involved with
you you are with Hacker 1's own bug
bounty program, but do you have any
insight into why that happened and why
we're not, you know, keeping bounties at
the same level or increasing them to try
to send positive signals to the other
programs um in the ecosystem?
>> Yeah. So, I the security team rolls up
into me and so um um that I am 100% the
right person and ultimately the one who
made the decision on that. Well, we've
got kind of a tale of two areas here
like you're you're very u the the AI
thing is a really fun conversation. This
is the one I probably deserve a little
bit more of a roast on because we do
need to be thoughtful. We need to get a
ton of feedback from the community on
this because this really is a feedback.
So, we're we're constantly adjusting our
our structure of our of our bounty
program, but one of the things we
adjusted uh this last quarter was we
were previously targeting the top 1%
benchmark for our program which meant we
were benchmarking ourselves against
Google, Amazon, Meta
I don't have similar security ambitions
but very different security budgets,
>> right?
>> Um and it broke a lot of stuff in how we
were looking at our program like we were
an ex we're an extreme outlier on the
platform and remain that and the team's
really trying to be more data driven
about why is that happening what are the
different levers here and one of the
levers they they came wanting to pull
was we'd like to follow the advice we
give our own customers and benchmark
ourselves closer to our ambition. So
we've changed our benchmarking group
from kind of the cloud hyperscalers to
high growth tech company and that that
looks a little bit a little bit
different means we're right now
targeting about the 80th percentile in
bounty. So still pretty competitive
bounties are still in the in the top
quartile but it was a drop before. most
meaningful drop was in lows and mediums
which is something that we um have has a
question that's been on the team's mind
for a while is we have historically
really incentivized the discovery of
lows and as we're in a period of pretty
intense transformation our own
technology stack we've seen a little bit
more attention go there than we wanted
to um and so we we moved our eth
percentile that impacted the the lower
tier of it the most um and then the
other debate the team was having is um
should we continue have one critical
definition across the entire platform or
should we start splitting it up based on
these things here? And the team landed
on one simple definition for critical
which meant there's instead of having at
most programs you'll see different
definitions of critical across different
assets. We've maintained one definition
of critical across everything that we
build right now. Um that's the one thing
I'd like the most feedback on and we're
going to be paying the most attention to
as we monitor this. But the team's
looking at it really closely. uh if
engagement does change or it looks like
our overall spend is is dropping. We
we'll be adjusting it back up, but think
of it a little bit as a data exercise
and um
>> it's uh I I really regret these things
are happening at the same time. I in
hindsight, we should have we should have
pushed this out a little bit a little
bit further, but they they they truly
were disconnected from each other.
>> It it's okay. And I think I think you
know hindsight is 2020 and as we I think
as we navigate these difficult business
decisions right I and and they happen at
at the same time you know nobody's going
to make the perfect calls. Um as I
listen to you you say that my response
to that is that makes sense for a
company that is running a bug bounty
program. I don't think it makes sense as
much for a company that is a bug bounty
platform, you know, because not not only
are like I I I like that you guys are
holding to, you know, I understand the
idea to hold yourself to the top, you
know, cortile rather than, you know, the
top 1% or whatever and but I also think
you've got to understand that what's
happening here as far as the bounties,
you know, sets trends for the rest of
the organization and for the rest of the
industry in general. So, you know, when
we see that as researchers, I'm not
super bummed out. I'm not like, you
know, the the hacker one is not one of
my main programs. You guys are you guys
are are tight. Um, but, you know, but
when I look at that, I think, man,
that's the signal that's being sent to
the rest of the bug bounty bounty
community, which is that Bug Bounty is
in such a state right right now that
the, you know, hopefully the most
invested player is decreasing their
bounties. And that is is scary.
Yeah, it's it's really good feedback. I
I do think that the thing we had the
most debate on and that we're honestly
still debating a bit is should we have
two bug tiers. So critical for us right
now is any confident information that
gets disposed and most of the criticals
we paid out were not access to bug
reports. So we've been debating a like
do we need a tier we we wanted to keep
the bar where critical was broader than
just bug reports but bug reports are in
a next level of impact for us like the
reports that we get where oh I could get
access to a vulnerability submission
that wasn't mine
>> those are those are really rare we
haven't had one in a while and they're
they're much higher level and so I do
think the both the incentive we want to
drive in the program and uh what we want
to signal to the broader community had
we gone with that kind of bifrocated
critical definition might have helped
it, but really good feedback. And anyone
else who has thoughts on this, please
please send it in. Surely we post it.
Folks that are engaged in our programs
or specific examples like the team's
really engaged, really responsive
feedback. And I I want to make sure we
got the mark right on this one.
>> Okay. Yeah. I I would I would love to
see a readjustment here um as a hacker
like and and either revert the changes
or um add some additional clarity to the
policy page or your your or maybe even
have like an exceptional tier, right?
Like a like a you know uh you know
>> exceptional tier or a multiplier if you
get access to a vulnerability submission
that's not yours. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I think that would be I
think that would be great.
>> Yeah. I wonder if like the bulk of the
funds that were leaking that put you all
over budget on that would were all from
the lows and mediums you know and
downgrading that would have mostly you
know cleared up the the any budget
issues or any alignment issues there.
>> So
>> it's more of a capacity and bandwidth
issue than a than a budget issue. Um we
don't expect the budget to change
dramatically because we're spending
quite a bit more in in in other areas
and pre-production testing. So, it's um
but yeah, really really
>> good good point. Good point.
>> I I and I also I'm looking at this and I
and I'm seeing, you know, lows going
from 100, you know, to a thousand down
to 100 to 200 and mediums going to
change.
>> Yeah. Well, I I I disagree. I think that
the I think that seeing lows go from,
you know, 100 100 to,000 to 100 to 200,
right? And then in mediums going from
2500 to 1,500 I'm much less worried
about. But seeing highs go from 12
12,500 to 7K and crits go from 25K to 15
says, hey, even our our, you know,
bigger vulnerabilities we're we're
paying less for. Like everybody
understands, hey, you know, look, we got
this HTML injection. We ought to clean
it up. We got to give them a bounty.
It's here's a couple hundred bucks. No
serious bug hunter is is going to
about that, right? But like if if we
give you a good report that's a high,
you know, and and we just lost five
grand off the top of that or 10 grand
off the top, like that that stings.
>> Does that make sense?
>> It it it does. It does. And I think it
it it adds more weight to the earlier
suggestion of we need multipliers for
the the categories of bugs that have
impactful submissions,
>> right? Because sometimes a CVSS high
isn't the same as a CVSS high, right?
[laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay. All right. Well, thanks for
listening to that, Alex. I appreciate
that. And and I would love to see some
some changes on on that table if
possible. And and if you do have the
ability to put out that tip line, you
know, as we suggested for um abuse of
hacker reports, either whether they're
getting fed into AI or that they are um
you know, being taken by triagers or or
members of the programs uh or whatever.
I think that would be a great thing for
the community. Um, so thank you for
listening to our our feedback on this.
>> I'm going to get the the the
instructions for the the tip line out
there. Ask the team consider an
exceptional tier and please keep keep
hold of us accountable in this way. This
is it. It's essential to have these
types of conversations.
>> Of course, Alex. Thanks so much, man.
>> Cool. Take care, guys.
>> All right, that's a wrap on the
interview. I'm really glad Alex came on
and discussed some of that stuff with
us. Um, if you guys are still a little
worried about this, that makes sense.
drop any concerns you guys have in the
Discord and we'll kind of discuss
further. And yeah, if we need to get any
more clarifying factors uh from Hacker
1. Um definitely sounds like they're
going to put together that tip line or
whatever to get more questions and and
concerns from researchers heard uh which
I think is a step forward. [music]
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, [music]
uh or if you want to support the show,
head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of [music] great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, [music] trust me. All right,
I'll see you there.